When I sleep at night I often wake up
我常在睡覺時
because of nightmares...
被惡夢驚醒
and in my dreams I see
在惡夢裡我看到
how my mother died.
我媽是怎麼死的
She died when she was going to buy
她死在去商店
something in a shop...
買東西的路上
I was slowly following her because
我在後面跟著她，
I wasn't wearing any shoes.
但我沒有穿鞋所以我走得很慢
When she crossed the main road
當她過馬路的時候
a car ran her over.
一台車從她身上開輾過
So she fell to the floor
於是她倒在地上、
and all her guts were out.
她的腸子都跑出來
and all the things she held in her hands
所有她拿在手上的東西
flew all over the place.
也飛散四周
So when I remember this kind of things
當我想起這些事情，
I throw money into the air.
我會把錢都丟到空中
Hey.
哈囉
What do you want?
你想幹嘛？
I'm looking for a place to sleep.
我在找可以睡覺過夜的地方
Where are you from?
你從哪邊來的？
Mekele.
Do you have any family?
你有任何家人嗎？
No, my parents are dead.
沒有，我父母都過世了
If you want to sleep here you'll have to pay.
如果你想在這裡過夜你得付錢
How much?
多少錢？
Show me how much you got.
給我看你有多少錢
Now, just go away and don't come back.
好了你滾吧、不要再回來
Give me back my money.
把錢還我
Go away!
走開！
I said go away!
我叫你走開！
Please, give me back my money.
拜託！請把錢還我
Go away!
走開！
I don´t have anything left, please...
那是我僅剩的一切了,拜託…
Go!
滾！
If I see you again
如果我再看到你，
I'll smash your head with this stick.
我會用這根棍子打爆你的頭！
I used to live in Mekele with my stepmother
我本來跟我繼母一起住在Mekele
because I don't have my own parents anymore.
因為我雙親都過世了
My stepmother hit me every day so one night
我繼母每天都會打我、
I decided to steal 150 birr
有一天我偷了150比爾
and ran away from home.
就逃家了
I was looking for a truck going to
後來我找到一輛要去
Addis Abeba and I found one.
Addis Abeba 的卡車
I hid inside the truck´s trailer...
我躲在後面的拖車裡
the trailer was so full
因為拖車很滿，
that it was going dead slow
所以速度很慢，
so it was easy to run and hide in it.
很容易就跳上去了
And that's how I arrived to Addis Abeba.
這也是我怎麼到Addis Abeba這裡來的
And ended up in the streets...
這也是我怎麼到這裡來的
Let's finish this chat
我們差不多了，
and go find some business for the night.
去為今晚找點賺頭吧
How do you feel now?
你現在覺得如何？
Are you still high?
還很嗨嘛？
Not so much,
現在沒了，
but yesterday it was huge, men...
但昨天真的很誇張...
My friend stole lot´s of money...
我朋友昨天偷了一大筆錢...
How did he do it?
他怎麼做到的？
He was begging so a guy took out
他在行乞，
1 birr from his pocket...
有個傢伙想給他1 比爾，
and accidentaly dropped 100 birr...
卻從口袋裡掉了100比爾出來...
Inmediately he stepped on the bill
他馬上踩住那張100,
and he took the 1 birr from him
再加上那1 比爾，
so he made 101.
總共101比爾
And do you know what he did with the money?
那你知道他怎麼花這些錢嘛？
He fucked all night with Bikina.
他拿去跟Bikina睡了整晚
Hey guys, do you know this kid?
嘿大夥，你們認得那小子嘛？
Yeah, I know him.
認得阿，
One of my friends tried to steal
我有個朋友想偷他的錢，
money from him,
那小子跑去報警所以
the kid told the police so they beat him.
他們揍了他一頓
I think I saw 50 birr on his hand.
我好像看過他拿著50比爾在手上
Really?
真假？
It could be enough for our party tonight.
那夠我們今晚狂歡了耶
Call him.
叫他
Hey, kid!
嘿小子！
Hey you! Yes, yes, you!
你！對就是你！
Come here, we want to talk to you!
過來，我們有話跟你說！
Closer!
靠近一點！
Show us what you got, kid!
給我們看你有什麼
Search his pockets!
搜他口袋！
Shut up and show us what you have!
閉嘴！給我們看你有什麼！
I don't have anything.
我什麼都沒有
Where is the fucking money?
你該死的錢在哪！
I don't have anything, I'm telling you!
我真的什麼都沒有，我說的是實話！
Just leave me alone,
不要管我，
the other kids took the money.
另一個孩子拿了我的錢
Which kids took your money, tell us!
哪個孩子拿的？告訴我們！
Just leave me alone, ok?
不要管我, 好嘛？
Hey, just leave the kid alone!
好啦！不要理他啦！
Do you have any problem with us?
你對我們有什麼意見嘛？
You know that he's living with us,
你明知道他跟我們
why are you doing this?
住在一起幹嘛找他麻煩？
Liar! we don't know this kid,
你騙人！
we haven't seen him before, he's new!
我們根本不認識也沒見過他！他是新來的！
This kid was in this place even before you were!
這孩子比你還早來到這裡！
Be careful!
你注意點！
you don't have the power to protect him!
你沒有權力保護他！
Come on, let´s go.
好了啦，走啦
We´ll be watching you!
我們會盯著你的！
Hey kid! Give us back the stick!
嘿小子！把棍子還來！
Hey, kid, give it to us,
小子！把棍子還我們！
can't you see he can't walk without it!
他沒有那個不能走路你看不出來嘛！
Give me back my money then,
那把錢還我！
I don´t have anything. Can´t you see that?!
我什麼都沒有了你看不出來嘛！
We don´t have anything either!
我們也什麼都沒有阿！
I don't have any family.
但是我連家人都沒有了
Neither do us!
我們也沒有阿！
I'm going to sell the stick to get some food.
我要把這跟棍子賣掉換點食物
Sell it? Give it back to me now!
賣掉？你給我還來喔！
He cannot walk without the stick!
他這樣真的不能走路！
Give back the stick!
棍子還來！
We're going to beat you up!
我們要揍死你！
THE HIDDEN SMILE